Finding Aid for Icie Gertrude Macy Hoobler Papers 1914-1979
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Subject files 1923-1976
  - Plymouth Training School (Box 18)
  - Premature Babies (Box 18)
  - Premature Babies' Milk Bank (Box 18)
  - Presbyterian Church, Ann Arbor, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Presbyterian Village, Detroit
    - Advisory Food Service Committee (Box 19)
    - Articles and Papers (Box 19)
    - Board of Directors 1953-1963, 7 folders (Box 19)
    - Constitution and By-Laws (Box 19)
    - Doctors and Nurses (Box 19)
    - Finances 1957-1961, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Founder's Committee and Alumni Meetings (Box 19)
    - Health and Activities Advisory Committee 1955-1960, 5 folders (Box 19)
    - Health and Activities Program 1960 (Box 19)
    - Marks, Ernest S. (Box 19)
    - Publications 1956-1960 (Box 19)
  - Presbytery of Detroit, Committee on Aging
    - Minutes and Newsletters
      - 1964 (Box 19)
      - 1966 (Box 19)
      - 1968-1975, 6 folders (Box 20)
    - Pamphlets, 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Protestant Foundation
    - Budget 1955-1960 (Box 20)
    - Constitution (Box 20)
    - Ecumenical Campus Center (Box 20)
    - Protestant Foundation for International Students at the U-M 1955-1961, 7 folders (Box 20)
    - Publications (Box 20)
    - Van, Amber Ply, Dr. Idell (Box 20)
  - R (miscellaneous) (Box 20)
  - Reynolds Medical History Library (Box 20)
  - Roberts, Katherine E. (Box 20)
  - Roberts, Lydia J. (Box 20)
  - Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research (Box 20)
  - Rose, Glenola B. (Box 20)
  - Rose, William C. (Box 20)
  - S (miscellaneous) (Box 20)
  - Scrimshaw, Dr. Nevin S. (Box 20)
  - Sherman, Henry C. (Box 20)
  - Shohl, Dr. Alfred T. (Box 21)
  - Sigma Delta Epsilon, Alumnae Chapter (Box 21)
  - Sigma Xi (Box 21)
  - Simmonds, Nina (Box 21)
  - Sinclair, Dr. Hugh (Box 21)
  - Smith, Arthur H. (Box 21)
  - Social Agencies, Council of (Box 21)
  - Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine (Box 21)
  - Society for Pediatrics Research (Box 21)
  - Society for Research in Child Development
    - Correspondence, Memos 1934-1955, 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Executive Council 1954 (Box 21)
    - Final Program 1957 (Box 21)
    - Monographs and Abstracts (Box 21)
    - Newsletters 1959-1975 (Box 21)
  - Society for the Study of Development and Growth (Box 21)
  - Stearns, Dr. Genevieve (Box 21)
  - Stern, Dr. Frances (Box 21)
  - Studies
    - Bone Density Longitudinal Studies (T.W. Todd) (Box 21)
    - Composition of Human Milk (Box 21)
    - Establishing Vitamin D in Cow's Milk (Box 21)
    - Human Life Studies (Box 21)
    - Maternal and Infant Nutrition (Box 21)
    - Roentgenographic Appraisal of Skeletal Growth and Development (Box 21)
    - Statistical Evaluation of Metabolic Studies (Dr. Bliss) (Box 21)
    - Urinary Pigment Study (Dr. David Drabkin) (Box 21)
  - Surgeon General, Office of (Box 21)
  - Swift & Co. (Box 21)
  - Sydney, University of (Box 21)
  - T (miscellaneous) (Box 21)
  - Thomas, Charles C. (Box 21)
  - Tisdall, Dr. Frederick F. (Box 21)
  - Today's Health (Box 21)
  - Todd, Dr. T. Wingate (Box 21)
  - Travel (Box 21)
  - Truman Library (Box 21)
  - U (miscellaneous) (Box 21)
  - United Community Services-Detroit 1956-1957 (Box 21)
  - United Fruit Company (Box 21)
  - United Nations (Box 21)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture (Box 21)
  - U.S. Department of Labor (Box 21)
  - U.S. Pharmacopia (Box 21)
  - U.S. Public Health Service Grant 1957 (Box 21)
  - U.S. War Production Board 1941-1944 (Box 21)
  - University of California (Box 21)
  - University of Chicago Press (Box 21)
  - University of Iowa (Box 22)
  - University of Michigan (Box 22)
  - University of Tennessee (Box 22)
  - V (miscellaneous) (Box 22)
  - Vitamins (Box 22)
  - W (miscellaneous) (Box 22)
  - War Ration Board (Box 22)
  - Watumull Foundation (Box 22)
  - Wayne County Medical Society (Box 22)
  - Wayne State University
    - Booklets (Box 22)
    - Correspondence 1931-1954 (Box 22)
    - Chemistry Department Advisory Committee
      - 1948-1955 (Box 22)
      - 1957-1962 (Box 22)
  - Western Reserve University (Box 22)
  - Wetzel, Norman C., M.D. (Box 22)
  - White House Conference on Children and Youth
    - American Dietetic Association, Follow-Up Activities 1960-1963, 3 folders (Box 22)
    - Child Health and Protection 1930 (Box 22)
    - Children in a Democracy 1940 (Box 22)
    - Conference on Children and Youth
      - 1959-1960 (Box 22)
      - 1960 (Box 22)
      - 1970, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - 50th Anniversary of the Children's Bureau 1962 (Box 22)
    - Joint Conference on Children and Youth 1964-1965 (Box 22)
    - Mid-Century Conference 1950 (Box 23)
    - Mid-Decade Conference 1966, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - National Organizations for Children and Youth
      - 1964-1965 (Box 23)
      - 1967 (Box 23)
      - 1968-1970, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Papers and Reports (Box 23)
    - Regional Conference, Detroit 1961 (Box 23)
  - White House Conference on Food, Nutrition and Health
    - 1969, 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Final Report (Box 23)
    - Panel Recommendations (Box 23)
  - Williams, G. Mennen 1960 (Box 23)
  - Williams, R.R. (Box 23)
  - Willson, Eva Donelson (Box 23)
  - Wisconsin Alumni Research Foundation 1935-1939 (Box 23)
  - Women's Hospital of' Detroit 1926-1951 (Box 23)
  - Women's Movement-Scientists and Organizations (Box 23)
  - Women's Research Club-The University of Michigan (Box 24)
  - World Center for Women's Archives (Box 24)
  - World Education, Inc. 1960-1973 (Box 24)
  - World Federation of Education Associations (Box 24)
  - World Health Organization
    - 1948-1956 (Box 24)
    - 1958 (Box 24)
  - X-Y-Z (miscellaneous) (Box 24)
  - Yale University 1925-1954 (Box 24)
  - Yearbook of Agriculture 1958-1959 (Box 24)
- Lectures
  - Maternal Nutrition as it Relates to the Health of the New Generation, Detroit Chapter-American Red Cross 1949 (Box 24)
  - Implications of Nutrition in the Health of Mothers and Children, American Chemical Society 1954 (Box 24)
  - Romance of Scientific Work, Western Reserve University 1955 (Box 24)
  - Lectures at Oregon State College, University of Tennessee, and University of Pittsburgh 1957 (Box 24)
  - Metabolic and Biochemical Changes in Pregnancy, University of Missouri 1957 (Box 24)
  - Physiological Basis of Child Nutrition, Oregon State College 1957 (Box 24)
  - Newer Concepts of Nutrition, Detroit Dietetic Association 1958 (Box 24)
  - Nutrition in the School Child, Public Health Nutrition Institute 1958 (Box 24)
  - Creativity Unlimited, The White House Conference on Children and Youth 1960 (Box 24)
  - Implications of Nutrition in the White House Conference on Children and Youth, Home Economics Section of the Michigan Education Association 1960 (Box 24)
  - New Trends in the 60's-White House Conferences-Why? Michigan Home Economics and Michigan Dietetic Association 1960 (Box 24)
  - Nutrition and the Teenager, Golden Anniversary of the White House Conference on Children and Youth 1960 (Box 24)
  - Personal Impressions of the Fifth International Congress of Nutrition, Ann Arbor Dietetic Association 1960 (Box 24)
  - The White House Conferences on Children and Youth and the Dietetic Profession, Virginia Dietetic Association 1960 (Box 24)
  - The Home Economist Listens to the Specialist, Michigan Home Economics Association 1961 (Box 24)
  - Motherhood-The Frontier of Human Development, Merrill-Palmer Historical Library Lecture 1967 (Box 24)
  - Nutrition and the Moving Frontier of Individual Human Development, Michigan Dietetic Association 1968 (Box 24)
  - Reflections of a Woman Chemist in a Changing World, Missouri-Kansas Dietetic Association 1969 (Box 24)
  - Highlights of Nutrition Research in Detroit and Michigan, Michigan School of Public Health undated (Box 24)
  - Individuality of Metabolic and Psychogenic Performance in Childhood undated (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous lectures Material for lectures (Box 24)
  - Notes for lectures, 3 folders (Box 24)
- Manuscripts
  - Prematurity 1953 (Box 25)
  - Child Development 1955 (Box 25)
  - Nutritional Value of Human Milk 1958 (Box 25)
  - Nutrition and the Teenager 1960 (Box 25)
  - Chemical and Physiologic Growth undated (Box 25)
  - Food Composition and Dietary Intake in the U.S.A. undated (Box 25)
  - Individuality of Metabolic and Psychogenic Performance in Childhood undated (Box 25)
  - Nutritional Value of Human and Cows Milk undated (Box 25)
- Personal and Biographical Materials
  The Personal and Biographical series (2 linear ft.; 1914-1979) has personal correspondence with friends and colleagues, award presentations, biographical and autobiographical information, school materials, and miscellaneous.
  - Argentine Dietology Review 1945-1946 (Box 25)
  - Articles and Speeches (miscellaneous) (Box 25)
  - Awards
    - American Chemical Society 1930 (Box 25)
    - Borden Award, American Home Economics Association 1939 (with later material) (Box 25)
    - Distinguished Service Award, Detroit City Council 1954 (Box 25)
    - Distinguished Service Award, Michigan Public Health Association 1972 (Box 25)
    - Fellow, American Institute of Nutrition 1960 (Box 25)
    - Frances P. Garvan Award, American Chemical Society 1946 (Box 25)
    - Honorary Doctor of Science, Wayne State University 1945; Merrill-Palmer School Citation, 1959 (Box 25)
    - Michigan Dietetic Association Award 1955, 1969 (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous Certificates (Box 25)
    - Modern Medicine Award 1955 (Box 25)
    - Norlin Recognition Medal, University of Colorado 1938 (Box 25)
    - Osborne and Mendel Award, American Institute of Nutrition 1952 (Box 25)
    - Woman of the Year, The Club of Detroit 1952 (Box 25)
    - Women of Achievement, City of Detroit 1954 (Box 25)
    - Professional Honors (Box 25)
  - Biographical Material
    - Miscellaneous and clippings (Box 25)
    - Campfire Sketches (Box 25)
    - Curriculum Vitae (Box 25)
    - Genealogy (Box 25)
    - Graduation Memory Book (Box 25)
    - Influences on Life and Career (Box 25)
    - School Papers
      - Biology Copybook (Box 25)
      - Relatives of the Plant World, Ten Men of Science, Astronomy (Box 25)
  - Children's Fund of Michigan
    - Clippings (Box 25)
    - Correspondence 1931-1953 (Box 25)
    - Letters received commemorating 25 years with the Children's Fund 1954, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Correspondence (Personal)
    - 1914-1979, 11 folders (Box 28)
    - Correspondence with Students (Box 28)
    - Letters of Recommendation (Box 28)
  - Curriculum Vitae (Box 28)
  - Education
    - Guidance in Career (Box 28)
    - Teachers (Box 28)
  - Grand Valley State College 1960-1971 (Box 28)
  - Hoobler, Madge Sibley Guest House (Box 28)
  - Iota Sigma Pi (Box 28)
- Personal and Biographical Materials
  - Meetings and Committees
    - 1954-1955 (Box 28)
    - 1958 (Box 28)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 28)
  - Mendel, Professor Lafayette B.
    - 1920-1930 (Box 28)
    - 1931-1936, 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Michigan Cancer Foundation 1975 (Box 28)
  - Pi Beta Phi (Box 28)
  - Presbyterian Village, Groundbreaking May 1954 (Box 28)
  - Publications (Reviews and Comments) (Box 28)
  - Women's Issues (Box 28)
- Photographs
  (also oversize folder)
  - Awards (Box 28)
  - Colleagues and Mentors (Box 28)
  - Family and Friends (Box 28)
  - Grand Valley State College (Box 28)
  - Homes (Box 28)
  - Hoobler Memorial Display. (Box 28)
  - Portraits and Snapshots (Box 28)
  - Presbyterian Village (Box 28)
  - Travel-Caribbean 1935 (Box 28)
  - Travel-England. (Box 28)
- Sound Recordings
  - Interview conducted by Patricia Pilling with Dr. Hoobler 1974, 3 audiocassettes (Box 28)
    (stored in sound recording collection)
- Artifacts
  - Honorary Award Medals (including Michigan Women's Hall of Fame) (Box 28)
- Published materials
  - Books and articles written by Icie Macy Hoobler (Box 26)
    (inventory of box 26 and 27 included)
  - Books and articles written by Icie Macy Hoobler (Box 27)
    (continued)